issuing credit cards as well British
insurer credential PLC is evaluating a
potential listing of ICS credential
Asset Management Company the company
said it plans to divest a portion of its
holding IC bank has said that it intends
to retain majority shareholding Yash is
here with more Yash well sharine after
27 years of this joint venture between
the ICI group and Prudential PLC uh
Prudential PLC earlier today expressed
its intention to sell a partial holding
which it has a ICICI credential asset
management company through the listing
of ICICI Pro AMC on Indian exchanges
what it exactly said is that it is
evaluating a potential listing of IC
credential AMC it is looking at a
partial divestment through this
particular IPO and listing of IC
credential AMC will be subject to market
conditions and the requisite approvals
they will uh provide further updates as
in when there is some process which
takes place as far as the plan is
concerned icci bank has also informed
the exchanges that they intend to retain
a majority shareholding in ic credential
AMC as I said it's a 27-year old joint
venture started in
1998 ICI Bank holds about 51% stake in
this particular joint venture uh they do
not intend to sell a single share as far
as the IPO is concerned it will be all
from potential AMC side which holds
about 49% stake and ICI ential AMC
whenever the listing happens will be the
fourth listed entity from ICICI Group
after ICI Bank ICICI Lombard ICI
credential life insurance and now of
course the AMC business in terms of the
asset under management and the size of
the company it is the second largest AMC
in the country with an AMC asset under
management of about
8.98 lakh CR rupees this is As on
December 2024 there are a few listed am
as far as India is concerned HDFC AMC
nipon life India AMC UTI AMC adya basan
life AMC and Sham asset management and
now talks of the next one in the form of
ICI credential life AMC